foreign
[Music]
shopping at my beloved local bookstore
trails and books they were the first to
support me when I became an author and I
hope to find myself working there again
very soon since today I felt like
shopping for books this was the perfect
place to go I came home with several new
fairy tales to read and decided I would
share with you some of my favorite books
in my fantasy and folklore book
collection as lately I've been in the
mood to escape to far off Enchanted
places and hope you will find some new
books to read this season and without
further Ado here are my favorite
Whimsical book recommendations
hello everyone I wanted to make part two
of my kind of book style videos uh
recommending books related to a certain
topic I'm certainly doing this for my
own bookish self-interest and again I
understand not everyone are readers but
those of you who are I thought that I
could make some recommendations related
to my love of fairy tales and folklore I
feel that there is so many themes in
fairy tales and folklore that are all
about healing that inner child and
nurturing yourself and finding that
truth within and not being afraid to be
who you are being someone with
imagination being someone who fights for
what they believe as so many heroines
and fairy tales do and there is no
season that feels more fairy-like than
Springtime so I thought this would be
the perfect time to share these books
with you and hopefully you might enjoy
them and they might inspire you I made
one video before on book recommendations
about elevating ordinary life and slow
living in mindfulness so I will leave
that link down below I will begin with
the book that I read most recently that
I did enjoy it is not one of my all-time
favorites but I thought I would share it
because it has been quite popular lately
and it is Emily Wilde's Encyclopedia of
fairies it is a very interesting book
about an academic named Emily Wilde who
finds herself in this strange isolated
town where she wants to study the local
fairies in folklore the fairies in this
world are very traditional style fairies
that are often not to be trusted and
rather cunning if you prefer Sweet
Little Flower fairies and Tinker Bells
this is not going to be the type of
fairy you find in this book however it
was very atmospheric and enchanting and
I really enjoyed it it is a romance and
I'm not always a huge fan of romances
mostly because I personally feel that in
many romances
um the characters often portray quite
unlikable quality I don't know maybe
it's just the the romances I happen to
have read but I still enjoyed the
romance so I will put this on your list
in case you haven't heard about it
before might be worth looking into east
of the sun west of the Moon by Jackie
Morris and also the Wild Swans by Jackie
Morris and snow and Rose by Emily
Winfield Martin are all retellings of
fairy tales and the reason I put these
books together are because they are
iconic to me because of their
illustrations the illustrations are
enchanting and beautiful and transport
you into another world and I highly
recommend them for their art if not for
their stories because I think both the
poetic style of Jackie Morris's writing
and the Art of Emily Winfield Martin is
just beautiful another kind of fantasy
folklore inspired book is daughter of
the Moon Goddess it is also has elements
of romance but it is not the very main
part of the book which I can appreciate
I like when the heroine has as a plot
and a story outside of the romance as
well and I found it to be very
enchanting and interesting I did not
enjoy the last part quite as much as the
beginning but it was very atmospheric
and it really ignited my imagination
sulin Tang as well has a lovely writing
style that I found very easy to read the
wolf and the whale as well by Jordana
Max Brodsky I want to say that correctly
while this book has elements of fantasy
as well as just within the normal
fiction category it does have
inspiration taken from actual history
and it does share some Inuit folklore
and legends that are beautiful and
really thought provoking and I really
love the main character in this book it
tells the story of an Inuit woman who
wants to be a warrior and it is a
interesting Adventure all about culture
clashes as well as going into the
ancient mythology of the Inuit people I
also have Woodland folk tales and I also
have another book in the same series
called Botanical folk tales and they
just go into several stories related to
Britain and Ireland that I really
enjoyed and were kind of simplistic more
fairy tale stories and they were
beautifully written I also enjoyed by
Oak Ash and Thorne by Melissa Harrison
the illustrations are just so cute and
the story is wonderful and of course
about little tiny people that live in
the forest I also love Howl's Moving
Castle if you were a huge fan of the
movie I will warn you that the main
character of howl is a little bit
different in the story he in my opinion
was not quite as likable as in the movie
but he was still really fun to get to
know and all the characters are so
Charming I also enjoyed Eva Evergreen
the semi-magical witch I want to say
that right it was just a really cute
heartfelt story very positive not too
stressful which is really good and it's
just a story of a little witch who is
starting to try to make her new life and
open a magical repair shop in a town to
become a well-respected witch it is a
really sweet story and I believe there's
another book out as well in the series
The Girl Who circumnavigated in
Fairyland in a ship of her own making by
Catherine M Valente is a beautiful story
if you are a fan of Alice in Wonderland
if you like that sort of kind of
absurdist fairy tale storytelling you
will love this I felt like it just hit
all those same cozy feels that I feel
when I read
um kind of enchanting nonsensical sorts
of fairy tales and it just makes my
imagination run wild so I really love it
for graphic novels I really loved the
moth keeper by Katie O'Neill I also
enjoyed the chapter book The Spiderwick
Chronicles I grew up with this series
and I've talked about both these books a
lot so I'm not going to talk about them
too much but yes and of course because I
love fairies and this is the cottage
fairies YouTube channel I have of course
the fairy handbook which just has all
the information you could possibly need
on the fairy folk and it feels like
reading a really long magazine it is
very easily digestible writing and just
a little bit of everything is in this
book and so you might enjoy it no matter
what your age if you love fairies like I
do this is definitely the weirdest book
I have but I personally love it it is
however not for everyone it is called
the land of stone flowers a fairy Guide
to the mythical human being and
um it is very strange the art in it is
very different you will see all sorts of
interesting art in it so if you like
kind of odd eccentric books you will
enjoy this one it is um has a beautiful
cover and inside it's about fairies
analyzing humans from a fairy
perspective and it is quite cute and
unique I'm a huge fan of the
storyteller's handbook on the back it
says you hold the map to places only you
can see there are no words to to this
book they are just images
and you flip through and you let these
images Inspire your imagination and you
can create stories of what is going on
in the paintings and the art is so
unique and thought provoking and I found
myself coming up with all sorts of
stories it is a very beautiful
meditative exercise as well stories are
doorways the imagination has no
boundaries no walls or borders all doors
are open to us especially when we make
them ourselves but that is my last
recommendation I do have other books
related to fairy tales and folklore but
these are definitely the ones that most
come to mind when I think of this genre
maybe if you are interested in kind of
fantasy fairies and folklore you could
look into these books or share your
recommendations down below that is
everything I actually don't know what
other types of book related videos I
should do so I'm going to stop here for
now but I wanted to mix these in just
now and then maybe once a month or so I
hope you enjoyed this and I will see you
very soon take care goodbye
[Music]
foreign